So I'm here in San Diego for the first stop on the What Would the Ancestors Say Mission-Driven Book Tour, and I'm being treated really lovely, and it feels beautiful, and folks are showing up.
The time she is. Man, when we heard about that Lincoln, about to bring that immense faith, proclimate, it's the fact that someone over here went stupid. Because you're correct.
For those of us who want to inspire courage in others, what advice do you have?
Do you demonstrate courage? We know that folks are not on it, so you're like, come, let's do courage, guys.
And they're like, bitch. Folks are like, I'm busy. I have a hair appointment. I can't do courage today.
I don't even know the next time she's going to be free. I can't. Who's going to be there at courage?
We have now become the tools of capitalism in a mental form.
And I'm not saying anything that hasn't already been said.
Like, this is not like, oh my God, she cracked a cold jaw.
It ain't bad.
However, the code continues to require cracking.
They keep coming up with new codes.
And because so many of us do not see that, we don't prevent it.
Tell us how we can really utilize what you put in the book as a resource and tool and reference guide.
But we don't have to stay here.
We had our land, and we were stripped from that.
And we were forced to establish something brand new here in spite of the constant threat of death, degradation, and terrorism.
And somehow we managed to form blackness.
Say books won't change the world.
Tell that to every colonizer that burned them.
Look at this.
They have a free bookshelf right here at Burst into Books.
You having a space like this in this neighborhood with a bookshelf for free books outside is handing out ammunition to the people.
Many black folks who served in the Civil War have said that the first time that they felt like they were seen by white folks was because they had a gun in their hand.
They were seen as a threat.
But they were also seen as capable.
Do it.
The Seals Squad.
All of these fascists do is burn books.
And I read somewhere that it's not that they're burning books because they want to destroy art.
It's not that they're burning books because they want to disrupt history.
They're burning books because they want to destroy memory.
They want to destroy the memory of what was there before they got there so that folks will not fight to get it back.
I start with the fact that it's not about being black.
It's about being people.
And, you know, Malcolm went all the way to Meta to figure that out.
And so that was a journey he did.
So I don't got to go to Meta to figure that out.
We have media companies that claim to be black media peddling a concept that questioning is problematic.
A mission is literally the thing you're doing to get to the thing you're doing.
And I ask myself, but what can we take control of?
Right.
So if I feel like I don't have control of that, then I start mapping a course.
But I'm also an artist.
So I'm, like, imaginative in what that can be.
And I know that for a lot of us, we are stuck to a grid of only what we have seen is possible.
I have a master's degree in African-American studies, but I don't realize the proximity with which things happened in the 60s.
In my mind, they exist as these separate, siloed events, when in actuality, they happened in rapid succession.
I have a master's degree in African-American studies, but I cannot tell you the contents of the 1965 Voting Rights Act.
I can't tell you the contents of the 1964 Civil Rights Act.
And I can't tell you how it was gutted.
No matter how tapped in I thought I was, I was left out.
And I had to check myself and get over myself and step in.
My final question.
You shared recently that witnessing the faith and spirituality of Palestinians has shifted your own views of a higher power.
Could you talk more about how that experience influenced you?
All at the same time, I was ostracized from Black Hollywood.
I was realizing I'm autistic.
I was deeply vested in the Palestine movement.
Okay, so my friend Laura Chang is an astrologer.
And she always talks about how, like, astrology just came to her.
Like, it wasn't something she had to really, like, study on.
She was, like, even when she started learning the words, it was, like, yeah, of course.
That's how spirit came to me.
It was, like, one day I, it was, like, I didn't get it and I just got it.
And I think the reason why it happened is because when I was ousted from Hollywood, I was disconnected.
And I gained a new consciousness around manufactured consent and the lies of our government.
I became available to being able to take in the indigenous knowledge of how we really are connected in the soil.
And there was a block that we prevented that before.
And it was capitalism.
Does that make sense?
Yeah.
People have the power.
And, you know, H-Rap Brown, make you rest in peace.
And I don't say rest in power.
Rest in peace.
Because you was here going through it.
And they was not giving you the care you deserved when you were locked up as a prisoner of war in the United States.
And I really want our ancestors to rest in peace.
Like, when I start in the book, I start about Harriet Tubman saying, like, every time y'all be on some bullshit, you are disrupting us.
We are literally rolling in our graves and Rosa Parks broke her glasses.
So, y'all need to get it together.
Can you just give people a good word?
Listen, the good word was just said.
Amanda was over here giving preaching to the people, telling us to make sure that we use our minds and our radical imagination to transform the world.
Two of the smartest people on the planet.
Zan!
People think I'm trying to scare people.
And I'm like, yes.
Yes.
They're like, you're being alarmed.
Because there's just a history of folks being reactionary.
And there's always people who are like, you know, this is about to go down.
And everyone's like, no, it's not.
Oh, brother Amir said, it looks like you about to give a lecture on the top, but then go to a protest on the bottom.
So, I'm ready with you all along.
So, to talk about all of those things in this piece, I chose to do so through different methods.
Because I am somebody who needs variation, right?
Like, I love a nonfiction book for the first chapter.
It's a lot going on.
Listen.
God loves us all.
We love him.
The ones that are truly wanting everything.
It all going to work out.
But them that ain't right, they going to get they do.
And they deserve it.
Because it's wrong.
And stop playing.
Love everybody.
Keep playing.
Y'all keep doing what y'all doing.
And keep loving him.
Enjoy the food, baby.
Enjoy the food.
We will.
They want you to say, I think, instead of, I know.
And so, you get trained in that, even with your own internal voice.
And you start doubting your internal voice.
And now, you've also been trained to be in fear all the goddamn time.
So, you can't even tell the difference between intuition and fear.
On Juneteenth, white people.
Where y'all at?
There's a couple of them.
Y'all see how to shut the ****.
On Juneteenth, you should just shut up.
Because there is so much reflection that happens in silence.
And I'm not talking about twerking.
And I'm not talking about having a good time.
That's not what I'm talking about.
I'm talking about the literal decision to be arrogantly ignorant.
Which is a very American trait.
Because in order to perpetuate white supremacy,
you have to believe the lie that white is supreme.
That's a goddamn lie.
There's nothing that supports this.
Nothing.
Look at basketball.
Y'all, this is one of the real ones.
One of the last ones.
One of the next ones.
It better not be the last one.
No, I know.
Ms. Mary Hooks.
And I just want to thank you on camera
for the continued, unrelenting effort and pressure
on these motherfuckers' necks.
Period.
Thank you.
We appreciate you.
Oh, we appreciate you, beloved.
Oh, my God.
You had it.
I'm so proud of you.
Thank you.
And I'm so glad I could be a part of your journey
to helping yourself.
Absolutely.
And thank you for receiving my assistance.
Yes.
She uses her voice.
She doesn't hold back from speaking the truth
and really just magnifying what needs to be spoken about
and then really creating a forum for people to articulate themselves.
I would also like to point out that coalition has been a thing, you know,
and the folks that I see say really generalized statements
never can tell me where their sources are from.
And I will ask them, where have you learned majority of your information?
And they will tell me from school, from mainstream media.
And I'm just like, neither of these places are created to tell you the truth,
particularly as it relates to Black people.
I like what she stands for.
I like how she thinks outside of the box.
She encourages us to also think for ourselves outside of the box.
There's an awakening happening because folks are starting to ask questions
and more folks are starting to say, yeah, when folks ask questions.
And I think that's a really beautiful thing.
And I encourage all of you all to do the same,
to, you know, get in the habit of saying why.
And not just about, like, external stuff, but internal stuff.
Why am I reacting like that?
I'm really excited today.
I'm just excited to be, you know, surrounded by Amanda and all of her knowledge.
To me, any adult who gets it, we should be in service.
We should be trying to figure out how do we get young people around us,
like, in tune.
Thank y'all for having me.
Bye.
All right.
Till 2020.
Why are you being so serious?
Oh, okay.
Till 2026.
We did it.
We'll see you then.